Hugh M. Hutton Papers
Hugh M. Hutton Papers
1932-1970
1952-1969
Hutton, Hugh McMillen, 1897-1976.
33 linear ft.
Over 3,800 original editorial cartoons primarily produced throughout Hutton's career with the Philadelphia Inquirer as well as two pieces of original artwork by cartoonist Pierre Bellocq and clippings of work by other cartoonists.
149068
Biographical History
Hugh M. Hutton (1897-1976) was an American editorial cartoonist who worked at the Philadelphia Inquirer for over 30 years.
Hugh McMillen Hutton was born on December 11, 1897 in Lincoln, Nebraska and grew up with an artistic mother. After attending the University of Minnesota for two years, Hutton enlisted in the armed forces and served in World War I. Hutton pursued coursework in art through correspondence school, the Minneapolis School of Art and the Art Students League.
Hutton found some success with a feature, Nutty Natural History and moved to New York City. He worked at the New York World from 1930 to 1932 and with the United Features Syndicate in 1932 and 1933, drawing illustrations and comic strips. Hutton relocated to Philadelphia and worked as the cartoonist at the Public Ledger in 1933 and 1934. He became the Philadelphia Inquirer's editorial cartoonist in April 1934.
Hutton held membership in several professional organizations including the National Cartoonists Society, the American Association of Editorial Cartoonists, the National Press Club, and the Philadelphia Sketch Club. The National Safety Council recognized Hutton's work with awards in 1951, 1954, 1957 and 1961. He was also awarded several times by Freedoms Foundation and he received a Christopher Award.
Hugh M. Hutton retired from the Philadelphia Inquirer in 1969 and died on January 2, 1976 following a stroke. The Hugh Hutton Award for Intaglio is presented to artists by the American Color Print Society at its annual members’ exhibition.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Hugh M. Hutton Papers are divided into two series: Work by Hutton and Work by Others. Both consist primarily of original artwork.
Work by Hutton (1932-1970) contains approximately 3,868 pieces of original artwork for editorial cartoons. Nearly all of the cartoons were drawn for the Philadelphia Inquirer from 1932 to 1970. Most date from 1952 to 1969. About 126 items are undated.
Hutton’s cartoons frequently depict issues of importance to the Philadelphia metropolitan area as well as the activities of the Pennsylvania State Legislature including work to revise the state constitution. Local issues receiving frequent coverage are public transportation and the Delaware River Valley. Unlike many other editorial cartoonists, Hutton rarely drew caricatures of presidents although presidents and their policies are heavily represented. Hutton also invoked the words of figures Ben Franklin, George Washington and Abraham Lincoln while commenting on current events. In addition to recurring characters representing the American taxpayer, Hutton uses a robed woman to depict virtues like peace and truth and John Straphanger to represent a typical public transportation commuter.
Single sheets of paper with information about cartoons not located in this collection and who Hutton sent them to are interspersed throughout the collection of original artwork as well as in the folder of notes. The series also contains clippings of Hutton's work, four negative proofs, a pencil sketch and miscellaneous notes.
Hutton’s original artwork varies in size, generally working at a smaller scale as his tenure at the Inquirer progressed. Hutton’s artwork was drawn almost exclusively in crayon (with traces of pencil visible); however his later cartoons feature some details in ink, primarily lettering. Works were produced on coquille illustration board. Cartoons from 1932 bear a notice from the World Feature Syndicate.
The bulk of the Work by others series is clippings of cartoons by other editorial cartoonists from the 1950s. Most of the items bear a stamp with a date and the name of the Philadelphia Inquirer, possibly indicating that the cartoon was also published in the Inquirer. The majority of these clippings of are cartoons by L.D. Warren of the Cincinnati Enquirer. Also in this series are two pieces of original artwork by cartoonist Pierre Bellocq about Algeria and also the European common market.
Arrangement of the Collection
Cartoons are arranged chronologically with undated cartoons filed in alphabetical order by caption. Clippings of work by other cartoonists are filed alphabetically by artist.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists including some of the artists represented in the Works by Others series. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Hutton, Hugh McMillen, 1897-1976.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Washington, George, 1732-1799 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Democratic Party (U.S.) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States. Congress. -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United Nations -- Caricatures and cartoons.; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Caricatures and cartoons -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia.; Economics -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Nuclear weapons -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Castro, Fidel, 1926- -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Khrushchev, Nikita Sergeevich, 1894-1971 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Civil rights movements -- United States -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Transportation -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Crime -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cold War -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Cartoonists -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia.; Editorial cartoons -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Elections -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Communism -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Taxation -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Editorial cartoons -- United States.; World politics -- 1945-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1933-1945 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1945-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoons (humorous images); Editorial cartoons.; Clippings (information artifacts); Sketches.; Proofs (printed matter); Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Hugh M. Hutton, 1964 and 1970.
Inventory
- Work by Hutton
  - Clippings
    - Editorial cartoons, 1957; 1959-1963,; 1965,; 1967 (Oversize 39)
  - Original cartoon artwork
    - Dated, Click here for a detailed inventory.; See below for an index to the cartoons.
      - 1932-1937, 1939-1940, 1945-1951, 14" x 22 ½" (Oversize 1)
      - 1952 Jan-Apr, 14" x 22 ½" (Oversize 2)
      - 1952 May-Aug, 14" x 22 ½" (Oversize 3)
      - 1952 Sep-Dec, 14" x 22 ½" (Oversize 4)
      - 1953 Jan-Apr, 14" x 22 ½" (Oversize 5)
      - 1953 May-Aug, 14" x 22 ½" (Oversize 6)
      - 1953 Sep-Dec, 14" x 22 ½" (Oversize 7)
      - 1954 Jan-Apr, 14" x 22 ½" (Oversize 8)
      - 1954 May-Sep, 14" x 22 ½" (Oversize 9)
      - 1954 Oct-1955 Feb, 14 ½" x 18 ½" (Oversize 10)
      - 1955 Mar-May, 11" X 14" (Oversize 11)
      - 1955 Jun-Nov, 11 ½" x 14 ½" (Oversize 12)
      - 1955 Dec-1956 Apr, 14 ½" x 18 ½" (Oversize 13)
      - 1956 May-1956 Jul 15, 14 ½" x 18 ½" (Oversize 14)
      - 1956 Jul 16 -1956 Dec, 13" x 18" (Oversize 15)
      - 1957 Jan-Apr, 13" x 18" (Oversize 16)
      - 1957 Jun-Sep, 13" x 18" (Oversize 17)
      - 1957 Oct-1958 Feb, 13" x 18" (Oversize 18)
      - 1958 Mar-Jul, 13" x 18" (Oversize 19)
      - 1958 Aug-Nov, 13" x 18" (Oversize 20)
      - 1958 Dec-1959 Apr, 13" x 18" (Oversize 21)
      - 1959 May-Sep, 13" x 18" (Oversize 22)
      - 1959 Oct-1960 Feb, 13" x 18" (Oversize 23)
      - 1960 Mar-Aug, 13" x 18" (Oversize 24)
      - 1960 Sep-1961 Feb, 13" x 18" (Oversize 25)
      - 1961 Mar-Aug, 11" X 14" (Oversize 26)
      - 1961 Sep-1962 Mar, 11" x 14" (Oversize 27)
      - 1962 May-Jun, 1962 Oct-1963 Apr, 11 ½" x 14 ½" 14" x 18 ½" (Oversize 28)
      - 1963 May-Dec, 15" x 18" 11" x 14" (Oversize 29)
      - 1964 Jan-Aug, 1964 Oct-Nov, 11" X 14" (Oversize 30)
      - 1965 Jan-Sep, 11" x 15" (Oversize 31)
      - 1965 Oct-1966 May, 11 ½" x 14" (Oversize 32)
      - 1966 Jun-Dec, 11 ½" x 14 ½" (Oversize 33)
      - 1967 Jan-Sep, 11 ½" x 14 ½" (Oversize 34)
      - 1967 Oct-1968 Jun, 11 ½" x 14 ½" (Oversize 35)
      - 1968 Jul-1969 Feb, 11 ½" x 14 ½" (Oversize 36)
      - 1969 Mar-1970 Jan, 11 ½" x 14 ½" (Oversize 37)
    - Undated, 126 items
      - A-W (Oversize 38)
      - Untitled (Oversize 38)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Notes, 11 Jan 1949; 1952,; 1954,; 1956 (Oversize 39)
      Order for drawing paper
      Notes about removed cartoons
      Weather maps
    - Proofs, 15 Jul 1960; 25 Nov 1965,; 21 Jan 1966,; 7 Feb 1966 (Oversize 39)
    - "Our Game Warden" pencil sketch, undated; 8 ½" x 11" (Oversize 39)
- Work by Others
  - Clippings
    - Newspaper clippings of editorial cartoons, 1952-1956; 1958,; undated (Box 1)
      Barrow, Henry
      Bastian, Robert
      Berryman, Clifford Kennedy
      Brett, Unknown
      Carmack, Paul
      Conrad, Paul
      Craig, Eugene
      Crawford, Bill
      Crockett, Gib
      Duffy, Edmund
      Evans, Roy
      Fitzpatrick, D.R.
      Flannery, Thomas J.
      Hungerford, Cy
      Herblock
      Hess, Don
      Holland, Ed
      Jensen, Cecil
      Justus, Roy
      Kuekes, Edward
      Mauldin, Bill
      Miller, Frank
      Orr, Carey
      Page, Grover
      Poinier, Art
      Ray, S.J.
      Russell, Bruce
      Seibel, Fred O.
      Shanks, Bruce
      Shoemaker, Vaughn
      Somerville, John?
      Stambre, John
      Temple, Keith
      Warren, L.D.
      Williams, Frank
      Wood, Art
  - Original cartoon artwork
    - Pierre Bellocq, 11" x 14" (Oversize 39)
      Jul 21, 1961: [Algeria negotiations]
      Undated: [European common market]
Index to cartoons
The following is a list of predominant people, places and subjects appearing in the editorial cartoons in this collection. The list is not exhaustive. Some subjects may require you to browse with alternative terms.
B= Box, F= Folder. For example: B1F1= Box 1 Folder 1.
academic freedom B33-B34 B36
Adams, Sherman B21
Adenauer, Konrad B12 B17 B24
AFL-CIO B4 B7 B13 B16 B18
Africa B3 B19-B20 B25 B32
Agricultural Adjustment Administration B1
airline industry B33 B37
Alabama B21 B27 B29-B32
Alaska B19-B20 B30
Albania B31 B38
alcohol B8 B21 B32
Algeria B19 B23 B26 B28 B31-B32
Almond, Jr., James Lindsay B20-B21
American Civil Liberties Union B24
Americans for Democratic Action B38
Andrea Doria B15
Antarctic B19
anti-Semitism B19
Appalachia B29
Argentina B12 B18
Arkansas B17-B20 B22 B25
armed forces B2 B4-B6 B8-B10 B9 B12 B14 B17-B20 B22-B26 B28-B38
arts B10 B16 B19 B25-B26
Asia B1 B7 B9 B12-B13 B15 B17 B19-B20 B33 B38
Atlee, Clement B9
Attlee, Clement B6
auto industry B34
automation B26-B27 B29
aviation B2-B4 B7 B12 B14-B15 B17 B19 B25 B27 B36
Baker, Bobby B29-B31
Beck, Dave B16-B17
Ben Bella, Ahmed B28 B31
Benson, Ezra Taft B7
Beria, Lavrentiy B6-B7 B12
Berlin B5-B6 B8 B20-B30 B37-B38
Bevan, Aneurin B9
Biafra B36
Bill of Rights B5 B7 B23 B28 B30 B34 B36-B37
billboard lobby B25-B26
Bismarck, Otto von B2
Blum, Leon B1
Bosch, Juan B31
bossism B2-B4 B22 B38
Boumediène, Houari B31
Bowles, Chester B24
Brandt, Willy B21
Brazil B26 B30 B32
Brezhnev, Leonid Ilyich B31 B33 B36 B38
Bridges, Harry B6
Britain B1-B3 B5-B12 B15-B16 B19 B21 B23 B30 B34-B35 B37-B38
Brown Sr., Edmund Gerald B23 B30
Buddhists B29
budget B2 B4-B5 B13 B16 B27-B31 B34-B35
Bulganin, Nikolai B10-B15 B17-B19
bureaucracy B2-B3 B5 B18 B35-B36
Burma B34
Bush, Vannevar B18
business B1 B25-B26 B29
Cambodia B29
Canada B13 B19 B28 B34
capitalism B37
Carmichael, Stokely B34
cartoons B2
Case, Clifford B24
Castro, Fidel B19 B21 B23-B32 B34-B35
censorship B27 B37
census B24
charity B10-B11 B12 B18 B20 B23 B25-B29 B32-B38
China B1-B12 B14-B15 B20-B23 B25 B27-B32 B34 B36-B38
Churchill, Winston B2 B5 B9 B31
cities (monetary aid to) B33
city charter reform (Philadelphia) B5 B7-B8 B13
city planning B12
civil defense B3 B5 B8 B11-B12 B15 B26-B27
civil defense B2 B10-B11
civil rights B3-B4 B14-B17 B20-B21 B23-B25 B29-B33 B35
Civil War B29 B31
Clark, Joseph S. B8-B9
coal mining B1 B9 B36-B37
Cold War B2 B5 B7-B9 B11-B13 B21-B22 B25-B26 B33 B36
college students B33 B35-B37
colleges and universities B33-B34 B37
colonialism B13 B16 B25
Columbus, Christopher B10 B32
common market B29 B31 B34-B35 B37-B38
communism B1-B18 B20-B22 B24 B26 B30-B33 B37-B38
Congo B24-B25 B27
Congress B1-B6 B8-B11 B12-B16 B18-B38
consumers B2-B4 B7-B9 B11 B13 B16 B19-B23 B26 B30 B34 B37
corruption B2-B4 B26 B31 B37
cost of living B1 B8 B11 B16 B18 B20 B23-B24 B35 B37
Costa Rica B10 B28
cotton industry B23
crime B1-B4 B7-B11 B13 B15 B18-B21 B23-B26 B31-B32 B34-B38
Cuba B21 B23-B30 B32 B34 B36
Cummings, Homer Stille B1
Cyprus B30 B35 B38
Czechoslovakia B6 B35-B37
daylight savings time B19 B29-B35 B37
de Gaulle, Charles B19-B21 B23 B28-B35 B37-B38
Delaware River B2 B7-B13 B16 B18 B38
democracy B5 B20-B21 B23 B26 B34-B35 B38
Democratic Party B1-B4 B8-B26 B28 B30 B34 B36
demonstrations B24 B29 B31-B37
desegregation B9 B17 B20
Diefenbaker, John B28
Diem, Ngo Dinh B29
Dilworth, Richardson B18 B22-B23 B26 B28
Dirksen, Everett B36
DiSalle, Mike B4
disarmament B1-B2 B7 B11-B12 B14 B17 B22-B25 B27-B28 B30 B32 B37-B38
diseases B21 B24 B28
dock workers B7-B8 B15 B23 B30
Dodd, Thomas J. B34
Dominican Republic B29 B31
draft B15 B29 B32-B35 B37-B38
drugs (use and selling of) B14 B37
drunk driving B4 B7 B10 B13 B18 B24 B33 B35 B37
Dubček, Alexander B36-B37
Dulles, John Foster B4-B5 B7 B15 B17 B19 B21-B22
Durkin, Martin P. B4
economy B1 B5 B8 B11-B12 B14-B16 B19-B21 B23 B26-B28 B30-B31 B33-B35 B37
education B1 B5-B6 B13 B18 B20 B26 B28-B29 B32 B34-B37
Egypt B3 B11-B12 B14-B16 B18
Eichmann, Adolf B26-B27
Eisenhower, Dwight B1-B14 B16-B25 B37-B38
elderly B16 B24-B27
elections B1-B4 B6-B8 B10-B16 B18-B26 B28 B30-B38
electoral college B5 B35-B36 B38
En-lai, Chou B11 B33 B37
Erhard, Ludwig B33
espionage B1 B5 B7 B12 B17 B24 B29
Estes, Billie Sol B28
Europe B1 B5 B8 B11 B15-B16 B19 B28-B29 B37-B38
extremists B29
Farley, James B1
farming B1 B3 B6-B14 B18-B19 B21-B23 B25-B26 B28-B30 B37-B38
Farouk I of Egypt B3
fascism B38
Faubus, Orval B17 B19-B20 B22
Federal Bureau of Investigation B7
Federal Communications Commission B18
Federal Housing Administration B8-B10
Finland B27
fire safety B21 B23-B24 B27-B28 B32 B36-B37
flooding B21
food safety B37
foreign aid B2 B6 B13-B14 B17-B19 B21-B24 B26-B31 B33 B37
foreign policy B5 B10 B13 B21 B38
Formosa B9-B11 B13 B23
France B1-B2 B6 B9-B13 B15-B17 B19-B21 B24 B32-B34 B36
Franklin, Benjamin B8 B13 B18 B21 B23 B27 B30 B35
free press B2 B16 B23
free speech B33 B35
freedom B6 B13 B15 B21-B22 B31-B32
Freeman, Orville B25 B29
Galbraith, John Kenneth B38
Gaza Strip B12 B16
George VI of England B2
Germany B1-B2 B6-B13 B17 B21 B24 B33 B35 B37
Ghana B27 B32
Ghandi, Indira B32
Girard Case B17
Glenn, John B27
gold B1 B35 B38
Goldberg, Arthur B27
Goldwater, Barry B28-B30
Goulart, João B30
government spending B2 B5 B19 B21 B23 B26-B27 B32 B34-B35 B38
graduates B6 B12 B14 B17 B22 B24 B26 B37
Great Depression B1 B19
Greece B30 B38
Greenlease, Bobby B7
Gromyko, Andrei B20 B22 B26-B27 B33 B37
Guantanamo B25 B30
Guatamala B8-B9
Guevara, Che B26 B35
gun control B35-B36
Hammarskjold, Dag B15 B25-B27
Harriman, W. Averell B3 B12 B14-B15
Hawaii B5 B19 B21-B22 B24
healthcare B21 B24-B25 B37
Henderson, Leon B14
Hershey, Lewis Blaine B7
Herter, Christian B21 B28
hijacking B26 B37
Hindenberg B1
hit and run driving B13-B14
Hitler, Adolph B1-B2 B9 B19 B22-B23 B33 B38
Ho Chi Minh B31-B36 B38
Hoffa, Jimmy B17-B18 B22 B26-B27
holidays B1-B3 B7 B10-B15 B18-B23 B25-B37
Home, Lord B29-B30
Hong Kong B34
Hoover Commission B2 B11
housing B1 B4 B8-B9 B14 B16-B17 B22 B31 B35
Humphrey, Hubert B12 B23-B24 B30 B36
Hungary B15-B17 B20 B23 B27
hunger B23 B28 B37 B38
Ickes, Harold L. B1
immigration B9
immigration B2
imperialism B9 B11 B15 B23 B37-B38
India B4 B23 B25 B28 B31-B32 B34
Indochina B8-B9
Indonesia B17 B32 B34 B38
industry (general) B1 B10-B11 B14 B22 B29
inflation B2-B4 B7 B17 B20-B25 B32-B38
insurance B5 B22 B34
integration B22 B32
intellectualism B7
Iran B3 B6 B9 B12 B38
Iraq B21-B22
isolation B1 B7 B21 B38
Israel B5 B11 B16 B19 B24 B34
Japan B1 B9 B24 B26 B38
Jiménez, Marcos Pérez B18
Johnson, Lyndon Baines B21 B23-B25 B29-B35 B38
Jordan B16 B19-B20
journalism B9 B17
judicial system B1 B12-B13 B16 B19 B27 B30-B35 B38
juvenile delinquency B7-B8 B10 B11 B13 B15 B17-B23 B26-B28 B30-B31 B33 B37
Kaganovich, Lazar B17
Kai-shek, Chiang B10 B20
Kasa-Vubu, Joseph B25
Kefauver, Estes B2-B3 B13-B15 B24
Kennedy, John F. B23-B29 B38
Kennedy, Robert F. B30 B35
Kenya B34
Keyserling, Leon H. B23
Khrushchev, Nikita B10-B11 B13-B30 B33 B38
King George III B1
King Jr., Martin Luther B35
Korea B9 B12 B14 B17 B20 B24 B26 B32 B35 B37
Korean War B3-B7 B29 B31
Kosygin, Alexey B32-B34 B36-B37
Kozlov, Alexander B22
Ku Klux Klan B3 B18 B31-B32 B35
labor B1 B3-B4 B6-B7 B9 B12 B17 B20-B22 B28 B37
Laos B5 B22 B25-B26 B28 B30
Latin America B8 B10-B11 B13 B23-B24 B26 B28-B36
law and order B17 B24 B31
Lawrence, David L. B19 B21-B22 B24-B25
Leader, George B11 B13-B17 B19-B21
League of Nations B27
Lebanon B19
Lenin, Vladimir B5 B19 B23 B37
Lewis, John B1 B4
Lincoln, Abraham B2 B5 B8 B10 B16 B23 B27 B29-B32 B35-B36
Lodge Jr., Henry Cabot B24-B25 B30
Longstreth, W. Thacher B11
Lumumba, Patrice B25
MacArthur, Douglas B4
machine politics B1 B6 B11
MacMillan, Harold B18 B21 B23
Malaysia B32 B38
Malenkov, Georgy B5-B10 B17
Malik, Jacob B3
Malinovsky, Rodion B24
Marshall, John B12
Marx, Karl B19 B23 B25 B29 B38
Matsu and Quemoy B11 B20
McCarthy v. Army hearings B8-B9
McCarthy, Joseph B8-B10
McKay, Douglas B4
McNamara, Robert B29
Medicare B31 B33-B34 B37-B38
Mendès France, Pierre B10-B11
Menon, V. K. Krishna B25
Meredith, James B33
Mexico B13 B32-B33
Michigan B2
Middle East B2 B10 B12-B21 B23 B25 B27 B29 B34-B35 B37-B38
Mikoyan, Anastas B21 B23 B26
Mississippi B23 B27 B30 B33 B35
Molotov, Vyacheslav B6-B8 B10 B12 B14 B17
Mongolia B13
Monroe Doctrine B24 B26
Morocco B6
Morse, Wayne B24
Mossadegh, Mohammad B5 B38
Muslims B12
Mussolini, Benito B38
Nasser, Gamal Abdel B14-B16 B18-B20 B23-B25 B27 B31-B32 B34 B38
National Recovery Administration B1
National Rifle Association B36
nationalism B15 B19 B25
NATO B2 B5 B18-B19 B21 B27 B33 B36-B38
natural disasters B12 B17 B27 B29-B31
natural resources B25 B29-B30
Nazism B7 B9 B26 B33
Nehru, Jawaharlal B7 B9 B11 B15-B16 B22 B26-B28
neutrality B3 B5 B22 B24-B25 B27 B38
New Deal B1 B38
New Jersey B24 B34 B37
New Left B34
New Orleans B25-B26 B28
New York B9 B12 B19
New York City B18 B31-B32
Nigeria B36
Nixon, Richard M. B3-B4 B8 B15-B16 B19 B22 B24-B25 B30 B36-B37
Nkrumah, Kwame B27 B31-B32
nuclear weapons B1 B3-B12 B15-B20 B23-B31 B33-B34 B36-B38
Oatis, William N. B2 B6
obscenity B22
oil B1 B6 B9 B16 B20 B26 B37
Oppenheimer contro B8-B9 1954
Organization of American States B25-B27 B29 B31-B32 B34
organized crime B1 B12-B13 B15-B19 B21-B23 B38
Pakistan B28 B31-B32
Palestine B23
Panama B30
Panama Canal B11
Pasternak B20
patriotism B12
peace B1-B28 B30-B8
Peace Corps B26
Pearson, Lester Bowles B29
Pennsylvania B2 B7 B9-B13 B15 B18 B21-B25 B29 B35 B38
Pennsylvania Constitution B11-B12 B16 B25 B28 B30 B33 B35 B38
Pennslyvania Legislature B1 B5-B6 B10-B17 B21-B22 B25 B28-B38
Pentagon B3 B5 B11 B19 B21
Peron, Juan Domingo B12 B18
Peru B37
pesticides B29
Philadelphia B1-B9 B11-B38
piracy B1 B25 B36
Poland B14 B16
police B7 B11 B18 B24 B27 B31 B38
polio B11-B12
pollution B23 B26 B33 B36-B38
Pompidou, Georges B37
Poor People's Campaign B35
Pope John XXIII B38
Pope Paul VI B32
Pope Pius XII B38
poverty B20 B30 B35 B37
Powell, Adam Clayton B34
prisoners of war B3-B7 B10-B12 B33 B37
Prohibition B1 B10
propaganda B2-B7 B9 B11-B14 B17-B20 B23-B24 B26-B28 B34
Puerto Rico B8
Queen Elizabeth II B6
Quill, Michael B4 B10 B25 B27-B28
quiz shows B12 B23
racial violence B17 B25
racism B25
railroad industry B21 B28-B31 B34
Rayburn, Sam B16
religion B2 B5 B10 B15-B16 B19-B20 B24 B26-B27 B33
Republican Party B2-B5 B8-B15 B17-B26 B28-B31 B34 B36
Reuther, Walter B18 B34
Rhee, Syngman B6
Rhodesia B33
riots B31 B34-B35 B37
Robinson, Joe B1
Rockefeller, Nelson B24 B29-B30
Rockwell, George Lincoln B33
Romney, George W. B30
Roosevelt, Eleanor B15
Roosevelt, Franklin D. B1 B38
Roosevelt, Theodore B19
Rumania B36
Russell, Bertrand B3 B34
Russell, Richard B3
Russia B2 B6-B19 B21-B23 B27-B28 B31-B32 B35-B37
Saud of Saudi Arabia B16
Sawyer, Charles B2
schools B7 B9 B13-B14 B20-B23 B25-B26 B32 B34-B38
science B14 B18 B22
Scranton, William B28-B31
SEATO B19
segregation B5 B12-B15 B17-B20 B25-B26 B32 B34 B38
SEPTA (and Philadelphia Transit Commission) B2-B5 B15-B16 B20-B25 B28 B34 B36
Sese Seko, Mobutu B25
sex crimes B9 B13 B17 B23 B27 B32 B34
Shepard, Alan B26
Shepilov, Dmitri B17
shipping industry B12 B26 B31
Shriver, Sargent B30
silver B1
slum clearance B14 B34
Smith, Howard W. B25 B29
Smith, Margaret Chase B30
social security B1 B8 B22 B24-B25
socialism B11
South America B13 B19
South Carolina B27
Soviet Union B1 B6-B7 B12-B13 B15-B17 B25 B27 B30 B34
space exploration B20-B24 B26-B27 B31-B34 B36-B38
Spain B1 B12-B13 B38
Sparkman, John B4
sports B5 B7 B9 B12 B15 B17-B18 B20-B21 B23 B25-B29 B32-B33 B35-B36 B38
St. Lawrence River B2 B8 B10-B11
Stalin, Joseph B1-B5 B7 B9 B13-B16 B18-B19 B36 B38
Stassen, Harold B2 B15 B18-B19 B21 B30
steel industry B2-B3 B14-B15 B22-B23 B27-B28 B30 B38
Stevenson, Adlai E. B2-B4 B8 B12-B15 B23-B24 B26 B30
stock market B11
strikes B2-B4 B6-B8 B11 B14-B15 B18 B22-B23 B25-B27 B29-B30 B32-B34 B36 B38
Students for a Democratic Society B37
Suez Canal B14-B16 B24 B34 B38
Sukarno B27 B29-B32 B38
Supreme Court B1 B3 B12-B15 B17-B21 B26 B37-B38
Sweden B3 B36 B38
Symington, Stuart B23-B24
Syria B17-B18
Taft Hartley Act B2-B3 B15 B23 B26
Taft, Robert B2-B4
Talmadge, Herman B14
taxes B1-B2 B4-B13 B15-B38
Teamsters B16 B18-B19 B38
television B2-B5 B8 B17 B23 B25
Tennessee B20
Tennessee Valley Authority B1 B38
terrorism B16 B34-B35 B38
Thant, U. B31 B34
Thieu, Nguyen Van B35
Tibet B17 B21-B22
Tito, Josip Broz B2 B14-B15 B29 B34
Tōjō, Hideki B19
tourism B29 B34-B35 B38
trade B1 B8 B11 B19 B28 B31 B34
traffic fatalities B1-B7 B9-B22 B25-B38
transportation B1-B5 B7-B11 B13-B34 B36-B38
Trujillo, Rafael B23 B26 B31
Truman, Harry S. B2-B5 B7-B8 B14-B15 B18 B20 B23
Tshombe, Moise B25
Tugwell, Rexford B1
Turkey B18 B30 B38
U.S. Constitution B1-B3 B5 B9 B11-B12 B14 B16-B17 B20 B26 B29-B30 B33-B34 B36
U.S. flag B9 B12 B14 B17 B19 B22 B30 B33 B35 B37
U.S. Postal Service B20 B22 B28-B29 B35-B38
U-2 incident B24
Udall, Stewart B26
Ulbricht, Walter B26 B29-B30 B36-B37
unemployment B1-B2 B23 B25-B27 B29 B35
unions B2 B5 B7 B12 B15-B19 B21-B23 B26 B28-B29
United Arab Republic B20
United Auto Workers B16 B34
United Nations B2-B27 B29-B35 B37-B38
USS Bennington B9
USS Hobson B2
USS Pueblo B35 B37
utilities B1 B3
vacation B7 B9
Van Devanter, Willis B1
Vare, William Scott B1
Venezuela B18-B19 B27
Vietnam B9
Vietnam War B27 B29-B38
Virginia B20-B21
Vishinsky, Andrey B4-B5 B10
voting B1-B2 B4 B7 B10-B13 B15 B17-B20 B22 B24-B25 B28-B38
voting rights B21 B23-B25 B31 B34 B38
Wagner, Jr. Robert F. B30
Wales B33